microhosting.in 2018-12-01

# MicroHost Privacy Policy

#### Privacy Policy

This privacy statement describes how MicroHost collects and uses the personal information you provide on our Web site: http://www.microhost.com/. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. 

### What rules apply to people residing in the European Union ?

For users residing in the European Union, please ensure you carefully read our EU Data Protection document, located here: <https://www.microhost.com/privacy-policy-eu>. It provides you with the information required to be in compliance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) rules. 

When you use our services, we send one or more cookies – a small file containing a string of characters – to your device that uniquely identifies your browser. We use cookies to improve the quality of our service, including for storing user preferences, tracking user trends, and providing you with a better experience. We may set one or more cookies in your browser when you use our services or one of our partner’s services. When you send messages, publish content, post material, transmit information or email through our services, we may retain the same in order to process your inquiries, respond to your requests and improve our services. Our infrastructure consists of servers deployed at multiple datacenters that are owned and operated by us or our partners. All information collected within our services resides on this network of servers

### Collection and Use of Personal Information

We collect the following personal information from you:

  * Contact Information such as name, email address, mailing address, phone number
  * Billing Information such as credit card number, and billing address
  * Unique Identifiers such as user name, account number, password
  * If you are registering on behalf of your organization, your company’s name, mailing address, and other company information
  * Your ip address at the time of you place our order or access your account

* * *

**Sensitive Information:** microhost.com collects and treats the sensitive information in terms of Information Technology Act, 2000 read with the rules thereunder, as under: 

* * *

### Choices for Personal Information

(i) **Account Password** : The registration may require you to create a password for accessing of **microhost.com** services, which is confidential and sensitive information, collected and retained within **microhost.com** database. But the said sensitive information is just used by you as a **microhost.com** user for gaining access to the services and is not used or accessed by **microhost.com** or its affiliates / partners in any way. 

(ii) **Financial Information** : The Bank Details may be visible on the cheques couriered to us for payment of any services, but the complete bank account details are never noted down or processed for any reasons whatsoever at **microhost.com**. Though we recommend direct deposit of payments in our Bank Account either electronic transfer or by drop of cheque. 

In case of payment made by a secured Payment Gateway at **microhost.com** , the information is processed at the Payment Gateway, who are PCI Compliant and do not retain the sensitive information for the period more than required. The said online payments are additionally subject to an independent agreement with the payment gateway provider, which is CCAVENUE, and agreement is <https://www.ccavenue.com/agreement.jsp>. 

* * *

As is true of most Web sites, we automatically gather information about your computer such as your IP address, browser type, referring/exit pages, and operating system. We use this information to:

  * Respond to customer service & offer requests
  * Administer your account
  * Improve our Website and marketing efforts  

* * *

**Choice/Opt-Out You may choose to stop receiving our emails by logging into your account and updating your notification selections or you can contact us at info@microhost.com We enable you to create an account, and share information such as messages, offers, & requests with others.**

* * *

### Information Obtained from Third Parties

If you provide us personal information about others (such as providing information about another individual to allow them access when creating a sub-account) we will only use that information for the specific reason for which it was provided to us.

* * *

### Information Sharing (other than sensitive information)

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement. We do not sell your personal information to third parties. We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as shipping your order or offering customer service (such as utilizing our ‘Live Chat’ feature). These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us. We may also disclose your personal information

as required by law such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request. if microhost.com is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information to any other third party with your prior consent to do so.

* * *

### Cookies

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. We use persistent cookie to store user id and session cookie to store different master ids. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file. we use persistent cookie to store user id and session cookie to store different master ids. 

* * *

### Tracking Technologies & Third Party Cookies

The use of cookies by our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers are not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies. Our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers use session ID cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. We use Google Analytics, a third-party tracking service, which uses cookies to track non-personally identifiable information about our visitors to our site in the aggregate to capture usage and volume statistics. Some of our business partners (e.g., Google Analytics) use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by microhost.com only and does not cover the use of cookies by any third-party.

* * *

### Web beacons

Our Web pages contain electronic images known as Web beacons (sometimes called single-pixel gifs) and are used along with cookies to compile aggregated statistics to analyze how our site is used and may be used in some of our emails to let us know which emails and links have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of our customer communications and marketing campaigns. We use a third party to gather information about how you and others use our Web site. For example, we will know how many users access a specific page and which links they clicked on. We use this aggregated information to understand and optimize how our site is used.

* * *

### Links to Other Web Sites

Our Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of microhost.com. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy statements. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy statement of any Web site you visit.

* * *

### Additional Policy Information

Our Web site includes Widgets, which are interactive mini-programs that run on our site to provide specific services from another company (e.g. displaying the news, opinions, music, etc). Personal information, such as your email address, may be collected through the Widget. Cookies may also be set by the Widget to enable it to function properly. Information collected by this Widget is governed by the privacy policy of the company that created it. Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs & community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. You can link to our site using social networking services such as Facebook & Twitter. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your sign-in information, name and email address to link between the sites. Services like Facebook & Twitter give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you want your testimonial removed please contact us at info@microhost.com.

* * *

### Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. Personal information, specially the sensitive information about users that is maintained on microhost.com systems and is protected using industry standard security measures. We maintain a variety of physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to guard your personal information. Also, we use encryption technologies to protect your account information, wherever required. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at info@microhost.com

* * *

You should be aware that microhost.com has no control over the security of other sites on the Internet you might visit, interact with, or from which you buy products or services.You should keep your user name, password or other access information safe and confidential to protect against unauthorized access to your account information and services. And you must adopt passwords that others may not guess easily. You may also request that microhost.com may delete your Personal Information from system and records. 

Additionally, you may delete your account anytime at your own free will. However, due to technical constraints and the fact that we backs up our systems at regular intervals. Personal Information may continue to reside in our systems after deletion for some limited time. 

microhost.com holding sensitive/ personal data or information of providers of information, shall not retain such information for longer than is required for the purposes for which the information may lawfully be used or is otherwise required under the User Agreement or any other law for the time being in force or unless ordered to the contrary by any order of court of law. The information collected shall be used for the purpose for which it has been collected. 

The information is collected and retained by microhost.com on it’s server located at Noida, UP, India. 

* * *

### Correcting and Updating Your Personal Information

To review and update your personal information to ensure it is accurate, you may login to your account or contact us directly at info@microhost.com

* * *

### Notification of Privacy Statement Changes

We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

* * *

### Contact Information

You can contact us about this privacy statement by writing or email us at the address below: **MicroHost** A-43, Sector 63 Noida Uttar Pradesh 201301 India +91-120-4840004 Email: info@microhost.com
